CHRISTINE LIU

christineliu816@gmail.com | 909.556.2003

SUMMARY AND SKILLS

Experienced researcher familiar with archival sources, database management, and content writing Capable of working with advertising campaigns and marketing materials; and providing administrative support Software: Adobe CC, Asana, Airtable, ESRI ArcGIS, StoryMaps, Wordpress, Autodesk 3ds Max; HTML/CSS

EDUCATION

DUKE UNIVERSITY | Graduate Studies

Dec. 2019

Master of Arts in Computational Media from the Department of Art, Art History and Visual Studies

UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA, BERKELEY

2016

Bachelor of Arts; major in History and minor in History of Art from the College of Letters & Science

EXPERIENCE

FREELANCE March 2020 - Present

- Plympton | Formatted classic texts for digital publishing as part of the Recovering the Classics initiative; provided notes on short stories by authors like Cheryl Strayed and Colm Tóibín
- Woodside.co | Researched and compiled a database of screenwriters for production development, proofread proposals, and conducted historical research

WIRED! LAB AT DUKE UNIVERSITY | Researcher & Graduate Lab Assistant Sept. 2018 – Dec. 2019

- Collaborated on Paul Jaskot's "Mapping German Construction" project with focus on the Kraków Ghetto, identified and created a GIS of perpetrator and Jewish spaces based on archival sources and Polish texts
- Created lesson tutorials for ArcGIS, and reviewed scholarship on Digital Humanities research and methods
- Cataloged and archived projects on the lab's site; wrote community profiles and conference summaries for social media/blog posts
- Conducted research into digital platforms, workflows, tools, and software of interest to lab needs

A NOISE WITHIN | Digital Marketing Associate

Feb. - Nov. 2018

- Season sales averaged 125% above goal, tickets averaged 80% seat capacity; coordinated ad campaigns
- Wrote, proofread, and edited blog content on Wordpress and designed e-blasts on Constant Contact
- Designed and created collateral for digital campaigns and social media (show info, signage, newsletters)

LOS ANGELES COUNTY MUSEUM OF ART | Registration Admin (temporary)

Sept. - Dec. 2016

- Drafted contracts, proofread curatorial justifications, and edited acquisition agendas
- Researched collection restrictions, and reconciled numbering conundrums and object records on TMS
- Compiled data on collection statistics, collectors' committees, and deaccessions

THE MAGNES COLLECTION OF JEWISH ART AND LIFE | Research Assistant Sept. 2013 – May 2016

- Researched artifact provenance through both online databases and archival paperwork
- Lectured for Pop-up Exhibitions, "Jews, Travel and Assimilation in Nineteenth-Century Bohemia"
- Created object descriptions and notes for over 100 silver objects from the Levy Collection acquisition